<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Catalyst Eastern Town Hall – Eastern Town Hall Proposals</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/</link><description>Recent content in Eastern Town Hall Proposals on Catalyst Eastern Town Hall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catalyst: Grow East Asia, Grow Cardano</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CeZynbrO-ak" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/catalyst/fund6/challenges/fund7-challenge-setting/campaign-brief/">Fund 7 Challenge Setting&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Grow-Southeast-Asia-Grow-Cardano/367250-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $250,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-question">Challenge question:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we grow the Cardano ecosystem in East Asia in an inclusive and supportive way? The same way we do in Africa, focused initiatives!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Cardano community leans heavily toward North America and Europe. Growth elsewhere requires our support and initiative as a community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A broad spectrum of people across Asia and connected to Asia, coming together and forming teams to grow our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves some questions about the quality of participation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The number of proposals originating from East Asian participants in Project Catalyst&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The quantity and quality of funded proposals originating from East Asian teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The observed impact of funded projects (meeting their KPIs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did we increase the participation of the Cardano community and Catalyst teams with East Asian residents?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was there an increase in Daily/Monthly Active Wallets (DAW/MAW) as a proxy measure of momentum and engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did we increase the number of Stake Pools and Stake Pool Operators based in East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We will also be asking some specific questions about the quality of the proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Is there good feedback on funded project progress, failure or success, that help us understand the nuances of deploying Cardano solutions across East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the novelty and appropriateness of solutions?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are we on track to improve the lives of people using Cardano in East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was social and environmental impact evaluation used to measure proposal performance?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the sustainability of proposals beyond the scope of Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As in Africa, raising the awareness levels of regular people in East Asia about blockchain and the Cardano network should be a priority for the Catalyst community. In this challenge, we provide funding for people who have learned about Cardano to take advantage of the community&amp;rsquo;s support and build on or use the Cardano network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The nature of the proposals for this challenge is open-ended. Their only requirement is to originate or focus on East Asia and include east Asian team members or focus on East Asian participants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, the overwhelming majority of Stake Pools reside in North America and Europe. The Cardano network will be more resilient when Stake Pools are evenly distributed across the globe. The Catalyst community needs to step up and intentionally make that happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano started life in East Asia (Japan and Hong Kong), and Emurgo focuses on East Asia. Let&amp;rsquo;s build upon that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-this-is">What this is:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A call to action; Activate the Cardano community&amp;rsquo;s ability to recognise, reward the opportunity to make the world a better place. East Asia is fertile ground for the adoption of Cardano. The return on intention (ROI) is likely to be high because projects in young and developing economies face less economic inertia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addressing different parts of the world directly and intentionally through funding challenges makes our community more accessible. It makes us more resilient. It helps us learn and understand the needs of communities that make up our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a vision that needs votes to become an achievement. When the challenge succeeds, the beneficiary is the whole Cardano community. It is a call to close our prejudices and open our eyes, hearts and minds to good people who lack the benefits many of us were born with—allowing others with fewer privileged circumstances to rise and succeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-team">Challenge Team&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This proposal seeks to include a challenge team. Unfortunately, the proposer&amp;rsquo;s have not had time to fully form a challenge team before the proposal goes into review. If possible, we intend to help form that team before voting commences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following individuals have offered to be on the challenge team.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Felix Weber (&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/pmd/3077912-48088?">@felixweber&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Robert O&amp;rsquo;Brien (&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/pmd/3056857-48088?">@wolstaeb&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The role of Challenge Teams is to steward the challenges in Catalyst - to present the challenge, track the progress, and report back to the community their perspective on whether the challenges were addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in being part of that team, please let us know in the comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This proposal is a copy of the &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Grow-Africa-Grow-Cardano/333079-48088">Grow Africa, Grow Cardano&lt;/a> proposed by @grebel and @archangelbob and is now one of the many &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26108">Catalyst Challenges&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Eastern Townhall Team Operation</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/eastern-townhall-team-operation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/eastern-townhall-team-operation/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MzemrlXpqnY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/catalyst/fund6/challenges/catalyst-value-onboarding/campaign-brief/">Value Onboarding Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Sustain-the-Eastern-Townhall/369124-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $10,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-statement">Problem statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Participating in Catalyst is difficult when you live in the eastern time zone and your language is not English.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="describe-your-solution-to-the-problem">Describe your solution to the problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eastern TownHall supports eastern countries with events, and translating content. The aim is to increase participants by 20% for each fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="relevant-experience">Relevant experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Co-Founders of Catalyst Swarm, Eastern Townhall, Catalyst School. IT &amp;amp; Software Engineering. educators and accountant in East Asia &amp;amp; Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detailed-plan">Detailed plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Eastern Townhall is a community-driven initiative growing Cardano in the Eastern Hemisphere and across Asia. We want to build a truly global economy and society. Our focus is on making the hard, possible. A place, a time, and a space where:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We can build knowledge, share information, connect and support each other.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Language and culture are not an barrier to participation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We learn how to apply the technology, and community, to address local needs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Show how to use Cardano to increase our economic wellbeing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enrich Cardano&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem with our stories, our energy, and our perspectives.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The eastern hemisphere, East and Southeast Asia region unite culturally and linguistically a lot of countries. With a population of over 1.6 Billion, our goal is to grow Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-problems-and-limitation">Current Problems and Limitation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Eastern Townhall is the result of individuals and groups working together. Each bringing a unique quality. We interact in and around the Cardano Community, focused on linking individuals and projects to Project Catalyst. But this takes time, effort, and incurs expenses. Having no pool of funds to draw upon limits what we can achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="proposed-solution-pool-of-funds">Proposed Solution: Pool of Funds&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To reach a global audience means meeting people where they are, in their country, their language and their culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are an active part of our Cardano ecosystem. Our cornerstone event is the weekly Eastern Townhalls. But we are doing more, so much more:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We make knowledge and content accessible to as many cultures as possible.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We host different events where community members come together&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We bridges to underrepresented groups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We integrate local perspectives to enrich the Catalyst Community; and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We listen! Gathering opinions and data to help us all understand.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We are doing translations, building community, sharing knowledge, enabling entrepreneurs, and growing Cardano.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Doing all that has costs, so if we are to sustain the Eastern Townhall efforts, then we need to secure funding in a way that does not add extra effort to what we are already doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This proposal is about forming and maintain a pool of funds (a treasury) that is managed by the Eastern Townhall Trusted Seed. A pool of funds to spend at our discretion. The treasury will be used to cover expenses, to grow and sustain the efforts of the Eastern Townhall. Expenses like translation bounties; production of content; paying for online service subscriptions such as Zoom, Github, HackMD, Statbot and others; paying for activities related to organising the Eastern Town Hall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simply put this proposal is about funds for organising a community group. Establishing a resource and distributed support structure that provides funds needed on demand without the overhead of specific Catalyst proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In return, we promise to report back financial statements on our activities and expenses. Translated into as many languages as we can find collaborators for. Our intent is to pioneer and prototype DAO treasury management[3] reporting. That is not a small matter and managing a shared pool of funds has plenty of compliance complications. The reporting effort is Similar in principal to the work being done by index.coop[4] and FWB[5]. Most DAOs are still figuring this out and the best practices are not even drafts, so help us work this out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning how the Eastern Town Hall is spending and allocating funds will help us attract future funding. Help collaborators identify opportunities to work with us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Help us scale and reach more people across the Eastern Hemisphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="kpi-measurement-method-and-goals">KPI measurement method and goals&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A questionnaire on the number of proposers / voters / advisors is conducted for each &lt;strong>fund&lt;/strong> in the community of the target country. The goal is to grow participation by 20% for each fund in the next 6 months. See our work on Catalyst Fund6 submission phase analysis[6] as a base line example.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="activities-to-reach-kpis">Activities to reach KPIs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Daily&lt;/strong>: Inquiries from the community about Catalyst are answered by our members in their respective languages. We will translate Catalyst content and publish it via our website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Weekly&lt;/strong>: We hold weekly planning events and meetups, sharing information about our activities with each community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Monthly&lt;/strong>: Our spending is reported. We will manage your finances in a decentralized manner using a multi-sig wallet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>By Fund&lt;/strong>: Surveys will be conducted in each eastern community to count the number of voters, proposers and experts in each region.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="details-and-costs-to-implement">Details and costs to implement&lt;/h3>
&lt;h3 id="budget-areas">Budget Areas&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Attendance at weekly project planning meetings that activate Eastern Hemisphere: 20 people x 2 hours x 4 weeks x 6 months x $ 15: &lt;strong>$14,400&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Financial management, progress management, monitoring and reporting activities, other new member recruiting activities, etc .: $ 500 x 6 months = &lt;strong>$3,000&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Common expenses: Expenses incurred across multiple projects (domain name, hosting costs, Zoom): &lt;strong>$1,000&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Total: (1) ＋ (2) ＋ (3): $18,400&lt;/p>
&lt;p>▲ Discount: $8,400&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Billed: $10,000&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Further funding requirements in future funds will be required to maintain KPIs that support Cataslyt&amp;rsquo;s success in the Eastern hemisphere&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have already started this activity and will continue to do so whether or not this funding is raised.We gave a 45.6% discount to free up funds for a wider project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE&lt;/strong>: The funds directly required for each activity, such as East Asian entrepreneurial events in the Eastern Hemisphere, meetups, translation activities, theme setting and management, etc., are not in the category of funds required for this proposal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="intellectual-property">Intellectual Property&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Participation in our community is covered by a &lt;a href="https://www.contributor-covenant.org/">Contributor Covenant&lt;/a>. A Contributor License accompanies contributions to our project. The copyright of anyone’s contribution is retained; the agreement simply gives us permission to use and redistribute contributions as part of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All our source code is licensed under the Apache License 2.0 - see our &lt;a href="https://github.com/c3eth/c3eth.github.io/main/LICENSE.md">LICENSE&lt;/a> file for details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our published content is licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Attribution-Non-Commercial-ShareAlike (CC BY-NC-SA) License v4.0.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="after-6-months">After 6 months&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have demonstrated our ability to grow Catalyst participation in the Easted Hemisphere and East Asian countries by 20% for each fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-team">The Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A collaborative effort, the team bring a wealth of cultural and technical experience to Cardano. We are all very active in Catalyst, and community groups across our ecosystem. We are a diverse bunch united by the promise of Cardano:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yuta Yuta&lt;/strong> (@yutazz) - Japan: Cardano official ambassador, Community Co-Organiser, Catalyst Fund 2 Recipient, certified public accountant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yan Tirta&lt;/strong> (@yantirta) - Indonesia: Cardano Indonesia community wrangler empowering his local community with education and encouragement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mie Tran&lt;/strong> (@mie.tran.0407) - Vietnam: English and International Business major with experience working with western businesses and translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Andy Sibuea&lt;/strong> (@zicozibu) - Indonesia: Leading blockchain education beyond cryptocurrencies and across Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tim O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@tobrien) - Vietnam: No-code pioneer. Facilitator in East African Townhall (EATH).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Greg Bell&lt;/strong> (@grebel) - Australia: IT consultant, writing Catalyst Challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Seomon Blub&lt;/strong> (@seomon) - Austria: IT consultant focused on the people-ware infrastructure for sustainable communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Robert O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@wolstaeb) - New Zealand: Financial systems Software Engineer, Community Co-Organiser and Entrepreneur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stephen Whitenstall&lt;/strong> (@swhitenstall) - England: Tracks and documents Catalyst. Helping communities like Catalyst Circle and Catalyst Swarm organise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Felix Weber&lt;/strong> (@felixweber) - France: Community Manager building bridges between people. Member of the T&amp;amp;M Catalyst Circle/Swarm/School.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team represents the initial Eastern Town Hall &lt;strong>trusted seed&lt;/strong>. There are no roles, no leaders. Rather people establish themselves over time, through participation. We overlap and collaborate with Catalyst Swarm[1], and Catalyst School[2] and other community groups across Asia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] &lt;a href="http://catalystswarm.com/">Catalyst Swarm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/CatalystSchool">Catalyst School&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] &lt;a href="https://newsletter.banklesshq.com/p/how-daos-should-approach-treasury">How DAOs should approach treasury management&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[4] &lt;a href="https://medium.com/indexcoop/index-coop-q3-financial-report-summary-1eda1a2ee629">Index Coop Q3 Financial Report&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[5] &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/po8qyk71aj3zfpc/FWB%20July%20Financial%20report%20published.pdf?dl=0">FWB DAO Financial Report (PDF)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[6] &lt;a href="https://forum.cardano.org/t/catalystfund6-submission-phase-analysis/70711">Catalyst Fund6 submission phase analysis&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Connect East Asian Entrepreneurs</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/connect-east-asian-entrepreneurs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/connect-east-asian-entrepreneurs/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ibm36IXxnYA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/catalyst/fund6/challenges/proposer-outreach/campaign-brief/">Proposer Outreach&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Connect-East-Asian-Entrepreneurs/369120-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $20,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-statement">Problem statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are no initiatives to attract and engage East Asian entrepreneurs where they are, in their local language.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="describe-your-solution-to-the-problem">Describe your solution to the problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Use the Eastern Town Hall &amp;amp; targeted virtual events to establish and support a network of East Asian entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="relevant-experience">Relevant experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Co-Founders of Catalyst Swarm, Eastern Townhall, Catalyst School. IT &amp;amp; Software Engineering. Educators and accountant in East Asia &amp;amp; Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detailed-plan">Detailed plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We want to reach the massive untapped potential of East Asian entrepreneurs. Meet them where they are, in their country, their language and their culture. The Eastern Townhall wants to establish a growing network of East Asian entrepreneurs. Where they can build knowledge, share information, connect and support each other. Thinking global, acting local.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-problems-and-limitation">Current Problems and Limitation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Recall a moment when you realised if you poked something, pushed it or moulded it, something new and interesting popped out the other side. We&amp;rsquo;re here again and this time on a global scale. We, the Cardano Catalyst community are pioneers in a new mindset. A new way of governing and funding. But to make a dent in the universe we need entrepreneurs. People are willing to take a risk, to poke, to push, and to mould new ways of doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reaching Entrepreneurs is difficult when language and cultural barriers exist. Local context may also have undeveloped startup funding programmes too. This can result in unrealized startup funding opportunities. Few East Asian entrepreneurs are aware of the opportunities and the technical, economic benefits of Cardano; Nor is there a full understanding of how to apply Cardano technology within local communities to address local market opportunities. We want to change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="proposed-solution-cardano-startup-month">Proposed Solution: Cardano StartUp Month&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This proposal is about running virtual events in January/February 2022 to develop entrepreneurs in Vietnam and Indonesia. The event aims to upskill entrepreneurs to develop market opportunities based on Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The purpose of the event is to build startup founders and Distributed Autonomous Organisation (DAO) collaborators.&lt;/strong> We are not building startups! Our intent is to educate. Focusing on experience-based learning by providing a soft way for the general public to access entrepreneurship and blockchain technology without risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The event will happen over four weeks:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Virtual Networking (Week 1 &amp;amp; 2):&lt;/strong> The first two weeks of the event is about Networking. Getting registered participants to meet each other, discuss their ideas and aspirations. Tutorial sessions will be held to help upskill and familiarise people with business design tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pitch and Team-Up (Start of Week 3):&lt;/strong> All participants come together for the opening event where individual participants can give a 60-second pitch of a project idea they want to pursue. People vote with their feet by choosing to join a team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Learn and Work (Week 3 &amp;amp; 4)&lt;/strong>: Over the next two weeks, teams start working together. Mentors are assigned. Special sessions are run with experts. Teams are encouraged to validate their ideas with potential customers. Throughout the two weeks, each team will have four 30min pitch sessions with a panel of mentors that help them refine their pitch and Catalyst Proposal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Pitch (End of Week 4)&lt;/strong>: All participants come together for the closing event. The pitch! Each team is given five minutes to present their market problem and their solution to a panellist that ask questions. To pitch every team must have submitted their proposal to Catalyst. When all presentations are given the audience will pick the winning teams. Prizes will be awarded. We all celebrate! At the conclusion of Fund 8, Catalyst Voters choose who to fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The event will focus on Cardano Blockchain solutions and place emphasis on using Business Model Generation, Customer Development approaches and the use of analytical tools like Lean Startup, the Platform Design Toolkit, and Wardley Mapping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the time proposals are submitted in Fund 8, entrepreneurial teams will have formed, worked together, finished customer testing, and developed robust business models.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-success-looks-like">What Success Looks Like&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The event is planned to finish on conclusion of the second week of Catalyst fund 8, Feburary 2022. Teams will be submitting proposals to Catalyst Fund 8 as part of their work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the event, at least 15 teams have managed to complete the process and submitted proposals to Catalyst Fund 8. Individuals complete the event with new skills, connections, and inspiration to continue their Cardano journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-performance-indicators">Key Performance Indicators&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For Entrepreneurs Startup Month, participation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reaches 100 individuals that form into at least 20 teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At least 15 teams submit proposals.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At least 3 proposals that are funded in Catalyts Fund 8/9&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At the end of the event:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We have increased our social media presense by 1000 followers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The event is covered by four major media outlets.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-one-month">After One Month:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Event Team formed, project plans and budgets finalised.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Event Website and Social Media Accounts established.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Event Online registration setup.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Event Promotional content (blogs/video) developed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PR and promotion of the event started.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-two-months">After Two Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mentors, Judges and Registrations all confirmed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Event underway and is being run.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-six-months">After Six Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>First event successfully completed and we are planning another improved event.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Three teams have turned into three funded projects that are activily building on Cardano.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-twelve-months">After Twelve Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Cardano Start Month/Week is an established event on the Asian Cardano Calendar.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="intellectual-property">Intellectual Property&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All our source code is licensed under the Apache License 2.0 - see our &lt;a href="https://github.com/c3eth/c3eth.github.io/main/LICENSE.md">LICENSE&lt;/a> file for details. Our published content is licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Attribution-Non-Commercial-ShareAlike (CC BY-NC-SA) License v4.0.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="budget">Budget&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Please see attached proposed plan for a detailed budget breakdown with planned activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Core Team &lt;strong>$10,500 USD:&lt;/strong>
Including project management, content production, comunity management, and adminstration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supporting Team &lt;strong>$3,500 USD:&lt;/strong>
Mentors, judges, special guests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Marketing and Communication &lt;strong>$5000 USD:&lt;/strong>
Media Visit, Influencer collaboration, Google/IG ads&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contingency (%5): &lt;strong>$1,000 USD&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="the-team">The Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A collaborative effort, the team bring a wealth of cultural and technical experience to Cardano. We are all very active in Catalyst, and community groups across our ecosystem. We are a diverse bunch united by the promise of Cardano:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yuta Yuta&lt;/strong> (@yutazz) - Japan: Cardano official ambassador, Community Co-Organiser, Catalyst Fund 2 Recipient, certified public accountant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yan Tirta&lt;/strong> (@yantirta) - Indonesia: Cardano Indonesia community wrangler empowering his local community with education and encouragement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mie Tran&lt;/strong> (@mie.tran.0407) - Vietnam: English and International Business major with experience working with western businesses and translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Andy Sibuea&lt;/strong> (@zicozibu) - Indonesia: Leading blockchain education beyond cryptocurrencies and across Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tim O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@tobrien) - Vietnam: No-code pioneer. Facilitator in East African Townhall (EATH).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Greg Bell&lt;/strong> (@grebel) - Australia: IT consultant, writing Catalyst Challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Seomon Blub&lt;/strong> (@seomon) - Austria: IT consultant focused on the people-ware infrastructure for sustainable communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Robert O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@wolstaeb) - New Zealand: Financial systems Software Engineer, Community Co-Organiser and Entrepreneur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stephen Whitenstall&lt;/strong> (@swhitenstall) - England: Tracks and documents Catalyst. Helping communities like Catalyst Circle and Catalyst Swarm organise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Felix Weber&lt;/strong> (@felixweber) - France: Community Manager building bridges between people. Member of the T&amp;amp;M Catalyst Circle/Swarm/School.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are working with Venture Centre[1], IdeaFest[2], and Catalyst School[3]; as part of the proposal, we aim to work with Enterprenerdy[4], Emurgo[5], local Universities, and IOG&amp;rsquo;s Catalyst Team.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] &lt;a href="https://www.venturecentre.nz/">Venture Centre&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] &lt;a href="https://catalyst-swarm.gitbook.io/catalyst-swarm-genesis/july-2021/catalyst-idea-fest-july-2021">IdeaFest&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/CatalystSchool">Catalyst School&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[4] &lt;a href="https://entreprenerdy.com/">Enterprenerdy&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[5] &lt;a href="https://emurgo.io/">Emurgo&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Connecting Asian Voters and Proposers</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/connect-asian-voters-proposers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/connect-asian-voters-proposers/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BT2-0tnZnzc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/catalyst/fund6/challenges/distributed-decision/campaign-brief/">Distributed decision making&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Connecting-Asian-Voters-Proposers/369063-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $15,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-statement">Problem statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are barriers, such as a lack of trusted information to voting caused by language differences &amp;amp; cultural exclusivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="describe-your-solution-to-the-problem">Describe your solution to the problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Provide trusted information by meeting people where they are, in their local language and culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="relevant-experience">Relevant experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Co-Founders of Catalyst Swarm, Eastern Townhall, Catalyst School. IT &amp;amp; Software Engineering. educators and accountant in East Asia &amp;amp; Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detailed-plan">Detailed plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Voting on how Catalyst spends the treasury creates long-term value to ADA, but with so many proposals, with so many new concepts, how do we make any voting decision? Now imagine how difficult it must be when you do not speak English. All Ada holders benefit if we develop better more inclusive and diverse governance processes and strategies. Unless the Catalyst Community and Ada holders level up our collective cognition, a random voting strategy is just as valid as a well researched one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-problems-and-limitation">Current Problems and Limitation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Language differences and cultural exclusivity prevents governance initiatives from scaling globally. The constant experimentation of Catalyst means we need to be mindful to include different languages and cultures. Avoiding one culture dominating the narrative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Misaligned incentives, scams and information overload prevent Ada holders from voting. In Asia and other non-native English speaking cultures, language barriers compound this. Language barriers are evident at every Catalyst stage. Survey results showed in the Japanese community biggest problem of Catalyst voting was the lack of Japanese support (45.61%). Over %37 of respondents highlighted issues with understanding the process- &amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the meaning because it was in English, so I voted randomly&amp;rdquo;. The weariness of scams and lack of trust between proposals and voters were highlighted too. Another %16 mentioned incentive misalignment issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="our-solution-eastern-townhall-goverance-forum">Our solution: Eastern Townhall Goverance Forum&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our goal is to establish a process, format, and event stage for voter and proposer onboarding. To bring voters, proposers, and proposals closer together. To establish trust between them. The focus is on six mutually reinforcing areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content production&lt;/strong>: Help Ada holders understanding why it is important to vote on proposals.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Eastern Hemisphere Language-specific events&lt;/strong> focused on voter education and discussion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A proposal &lt;strong>language translation pipeline&lt;/strong> to help proposers reach the wider East Asian community.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Language-specific Catalyst Swarm Ideafests&lt;/strong> as a stage for building voter awareness, engagement, and trust.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Social Media Marketing&lt;/strong>: socialise voter content and messaging across our social media channels; and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conduct &lt;strong>routine surveys and user research&lt;/strong> to help understand individual attitudes to Catalyst and proposal formats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The proposal is seeking funds to help develop a programme specifically designed to help connect voters with proposals and proposers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together these activities form a programme we call the &lt;strong>Eastern Townhall Forum&lt;/strong>. Our cornerstone event is the weekly Eastern Townhalls. But we are doing more. We are doing translations, building community, sharing knowledge, educating, enabling entrepreneurs, and growing Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Eastern Townhall trusted seed are an active part of our Cardano ecosystem. Listening and engaging with members of the community. Sharing what we learn. For instance &lt;strong>Yuta Yuta&lt;/strong> recently completed one of his many surveys of the Japanese community[1] that this proposal draws upon. We want to do more of this across all the communities. We would like to help improve the user experience for voters. Feeding our collective insights back into Project Catalyst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Help us improve decision making across the Eastern Hemisphere by making Catalyst voting more accessible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-success-looks-like">What Success Looks Like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Participation in Eastern Townhall events has increased and maintains the vibrancy of the new and regular community members. More Catalyst proposers engage with the Asian community. Even if that is just translation of proposals, content, or DApps for the Asian markets. Additionally, Asian proposers find their crowd. They are able to be funded because there is a strong body of Asian voters participating in Catalyst. Survey results show an increase in voter engagement with proposers, the Catalyst process, and deliberations before voting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-performance-indicators">Key Performance Indicators&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our primary tool for measuring performance is our voter survey. We will conduct these on a regular basis across Asian countries. Based on the surveys during and after a fund we expect to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Increase Asian voter participation by 30% from the previous funds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Increase Asian participation in Catalyst by 20% from the previous fund.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Uncertainty around Catalyst and voting decreases 25% from the previous fund.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The Eastern Townhall Meetup is our primary stage where Ada holders and people interested in Cardano can come and meet community members. Through that platform and social media, people learn and feel comfortable going further. Therefore key engagement metrics indicate our success in bridging voters and proposers together:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Easter Townhall meetup average weekly numbers increase 25% for each fund.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Catalyst Proposals available in four languages &lt;em>(ID, JP, KR, VN)&lt;/em> increase 50% for each fund.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eastern Townhall Social Media accounts increase followers by 1000 new followers in six months.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-one-month">After One Month:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Completed our first pan-Asia voter survey across four Asian countries &lt;em>(ID, JP, KR, VN)&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Language-Specific events – Voter Education &amp;amp; Catalyst Swarm&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-three-months">After Three Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Produced our Voter Education videos&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translated Catalyst voter materials in four Asian languages &lt;em>(ID, JP, KR, VN)&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Held the first formal language specific Eastern Townhall - Catalyst Swarm IdeaFests. (A test run for Fund 6 is being done to find our feet).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-six-months">After Six Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Completed six voter surveys across four Asian countries &lt;em>(ID, JP, KR, VN)&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed a retrospective on our activities.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="after-twelve-months">After Twelve Months:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We have incorporated the content and practices need to engage with Asian voters and proposers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Our monthly surveys continue and show forward momentum.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Our content continues to engage members of the community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We have translated our content and Catalyst material to more languages across Asia.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="intellectual-property">Intellectual Property&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All our source code is licensed under the Apache License 2.0 - see our &lt;a href="https://github.com/c3eth/c3eth.github.io/main/LICENSE.md">LICENSE&lt;/a> file for details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our published content is licensed under the &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Attribution-Non-Commercial-ShareAlike (CC BY-NC-SA) License v4.0.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="budget">Budget&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Please see the attached proposed plan for a detailed budget breakdown with planned activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Core Team &lt;strong>$4,000 USD:&lt;/strong>
Including project management and adminstration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supporting Team &lt;strong>$5,000 USD:&lt;/strong>
Community Managers/Leaders, Moderators, and Interpreters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphics and Video Content Production &lt;strong>$4500 USD:&lt;/strong>
Educational videos, social media posters/video, and translations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contingency (%10): &lt;strong>$1,500 USD&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Labour costs are a lot lower in Vietnam and Indonesia we are able to do more. However, these costs need to be normalised to a global median for kind work/skill. Not everyone lives in Vietnam/Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-team">The Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A collaborative effort, the team bring a wealth of cultural and technical experience to Cardano. We are all very active in Catalyst, and community groups across our ecosystem. We are a diverse bunch united by the promise of Cardano:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yuta Yuta&lt;/strong> (@yutazz) - Japan: Cardano official ambassador, Community Co-Organiser, Catalyst Fund 2 Recipient, certified public accountant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yan Tirta&lt;/strong> (@yantirta) - Indonesia: Cardano Indonesia community wrangler empowering his local community with education and encouragement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mie Tran&lt;/strong> (@mie.tran.0407) - Vietnam: English and International Business major with experience working with western businesses and translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Andy Sibuea&lt;/strong> (@zicozibu) - Indonesia: Leading blockchain education beyond cryptocurrencies and across Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tim O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@tobrien) - Vietnam: No-code pioneer. Facilitator in East African Townhall (EATH).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Greg Bell&lt;/strong> (@grebel) - Australia: IT consultant, writing Catalyst Challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Seomon Blub&lt;/strong> (@seomon) - Austria: IT consultant focused on the people-ware infrastructure for sustainable communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Robert O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@wolstaeb) - New Zealand: Financial systems Software Engineer, Community Co-Organiser and Entrepreneur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stephen Whitenstall&lt;/strong> (@swhitenstall) - England: Tracks and documents Catalyst. Helping communities like Catalyst Circle and Catalyst Swarm organise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Felix Weber&lt;/strong> (@felixweber) - France: Community Manager building bridges between people. Member of the T&amp;amp;M Catalyst Circle/Swarm/School.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team represents the initial Eastern Town Hall &lt;strong>trusted seed&lt;/strong>. There are no roles, no leaders. Rather people establish themselves over time, through participation. We overlap and collaborate with Catalyst Swarm[2], and Catalyst School[3] and other community groups across Asia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] &lt;a href="https://t.me/ProjectCatalystChat/53776">Japanese community Survey August 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] &lt;a href="http://catalystswarm.com/">Catalyst Swarm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] &lt;a href="https://linktr.ee/CatalystSchool">Catalyst School&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: On-boarding East Asia Today!</title><link>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/on-board-east-asia-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/catalyst/fund6/eth-proposals/on-board-east-asia-today/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/catalyst/fund6/challenges/multilingual-resources/campaign-brief/">Multilingual resources&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/On-boarding-East-Asia-Today!/368844-48088?">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $12,500&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/JFsp5WD.png" alt="English Proficiency Index: www.ef.com/epi">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problem-statement">Problem statement&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Despite a population of billions, East Asians are underrepresented in Catalyst due to a lack of localised content.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="describe-your-solution-to-the-problem">Describe your solution to the problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Setup a translation pipeline that will translate catalyst documentation &amp;amp; proposals across as many languages in East Asia as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="relevant-experience">Relevant experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Co-Founders of Catalyst Swarm, Eastern Townhall, Catalyst School. IT &amp;amp; Software Engineering. educators and accountant in East Asia &amp;amp; Japan.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detailed-plan">Detailed plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>East Asia and Southeast Asia region unites culturally and linguistically diverse countries. People in these communities are excited about getting involved in the Cardano ecosystem. Despite having a population of 1.6 Billion, Catalyst has seen very few proposals from East Asia and Southeast Asian regions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="current-problems-and-limitation">Current Problems and Limitation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Across East Asia and Southeast Asian regions, English is not routinely spoken and a web of regional languages are used [1].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Language barriers reduce participation in Catalyst. It limits the potential growth of Cardano adoption and utility in this region. We experience this, we hear this from our communities. We know Cardano is missing our stories, our energy, and our perspectives of how to use Cardano to increase economic wellbeing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="proposed-solution-translation-pipeline-and-automation">Proposed Solution: Translation Pipeline and Automation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our objective is to build and document a streamlined process for content translation and start the development of localised content. We have already set up a simple translation pipeline[2] using Git, Hugo, and Github Actions. We&amp;rsquo;ve tested several translation services such as Crowdin[3], Lokalize[4], PoEditor[5], and GitLozalise[6] for the Eastern Townhall to help us organise and gain some experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our initial objective is simple: to get a lot of existing Cardano and Catalyst material translated into as many languages of the East and Southeast Asian regions using a semi-automated system. Gaining experience and building community. Documenting what we do and how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By semi-automated system, we do not mean machine translation. While Machine translation is helpful as a starting point, it has difficulty with specialised terms and does not read naturally. Human translations will always have a slight advantage. A semi-automated system refers to an ability to queue a piece of work for translation, which may include feeding it through a machine translation service, have it worked on by someone, reviewed, and then published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will start to embrace and extend the excellent localisation documentation processes established by Kubernetes SIG Docs group[7] to help us. Adapting the processes to accommodate the varying technical skills and future directions we want to take.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="work-streams">Work Streams&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To establish a functioning and sustainable translation pipeline, we are seeking initial funding to help develop the work we have already started. The funding will cover five workstreams:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Evaluation of translation services and their integration:
with Git, Github, Ideascale, and the Markdown-based documentation efforts of the Cardano Foundation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design, configuration, testing of a translation pipeline:
The goal is to have a small scale process in place that is easy enough to follow and requires minimal supervision.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documenting translation process &amp;amp; development of tutorial material:
Embrace and extend the Kubernettes SIG Doc[7] processes to help with our own needs. Developing localised tutorial content to onboard future translators.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Train the trainers:
Run training sessions with Eastern Townhall members to a level of competence in the process such that they can train others.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translations:
Getting up to speed on our workflow is going to require some hands-on tinkering and experience. We aim to translate a selection of Catalyst Guides, Community Advisor, voter education and our own material. That takes time and effort for each language.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="getting-scale-earn-to-learn">Getting Scale: Earn-to-Learn&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To get true scale, translations and localisation standards, automation, and skills need to be developed so we can outsource localisation to the wider Cardano community. Doing translation and localisation work as a way to get more involved in Cardano and the different communities. Doing translation and localisation work; learning and earning. Doing translation and localisation work to build a reputation and earn Ada. We see a future that leverages Metadata, Native Assets, Non-Fungible Tokens (NFT), Machine-Learning, and Atala Prism on the Cardano blockchain to give us language and cultural reach. However, starting simply first.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="collaboration">Collaboration&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Translation and localisation of content is a general issue across many groups working in Cardano and Catalyst. We do not plan to do this work alone or exclusively. In the Eastern Town Hall, we are at the forefront of managing many languages and cultures, our plan is to develop practices and automated processes for our own purposes, and share them widely. Everything we learn and do, we hope will inform the Cardano ecosystem at large.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-success-looks-like">What Success Looks Like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Near-term the Eastern Townhall is able to translate and host Catalyst Proposals as they are finalised. Translated for our four initial languages in the Asian region. Funded project reports are integrated and translated too. We have also translated, and maintain those translations, of key Cardano and Catalyst documents and guides.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mid-term we would like to expand the languages translated, and we are actively working with other groups across the Cardano Ecosystem to do this work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Longer-term success means we&amp;rsquo;ve established a whole decentralised workflow for translation and interpretation of any document, video, podcast etc. using the Cardano Network as the coordinating backbone. Where one of the simplest ways to onboard and earn ADA in the Cardano ecosystem system is to help translate, transcribe or interpret material (no harm in dreaming big!).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="key-performance-indicators">Key Performance Indicators&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Since we are using Git, and Github for the Eastern Townhall planning, organisation, documentation, metrics are derived from Github activity and engagement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Metric&lt;/strong>: Project Velocity[8], defined as a combination of base activity metric of commits and pull-requests taken from Github.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Activity Metrics&lt;/strong>: captured as project activity in Github and cadence documents added and the speed of translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Community Metrics&lt;/strong>: engagement behaviours broken down into four categories[9] for the Eastern Townhall website, to measure how our work is being spread and used in the Cardano ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="after-one-month">After One Month:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Eastern Townhall website information architecture has been developed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Primary content for the initial website has been identified and ported to Markdown.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The entire Eastern Townhall website is translated.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="after-three-months">After Three Months:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We have established a semi-automated translation pipeline driven by Git Pull requests.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evaluated and tested different translations services as a means to simplify translation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documented our initial translation process and trained the trainers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expanded formats for translations to include video subtitles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Issuing NFTs for skills, language, and attribution/contribution tracking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="after-six-months">After Six Months:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>On-boarding more members of the Cardano Community to do translations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Added two more Eastern hemisphere languages to our core set.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tutorial material (documentation and videos) is developed and translated to help onboard new contributors and languages.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="after-twelve-months">After Twelve Months:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All Catalyst Proposals and Funded Projects are translated and published within days of being produced.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We have expanded our core language set to include the ten languages from the Eastern hemisphere.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The translation project is self-sustaining because projects/teams/businesses want to reach our audience in their native language.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Cardano ecosystem coalesce around similar standards for document management and their translations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="licensing">Licensing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>All our source code will be licensed under a free and open-source (OSI) license e.g. MIT, and contributions must be contributed patent-free. Contributors will be required to agree to a Contributor Covernant[10].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Published content will be licensed under the Creative Attribution-Non-Commercial-ShareAlike International (CC BY-NC-SA) License v4.0. Any meta-data specifications will be published under a Creative Commons Attribution-NoDerivatives 4.0 International (CC BY-ND 4.0) license. Where and when applicable metadata specifications for document identification and provenance will be submitted as Cardano Improvement Proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Code, documentation, project activity is made available on Github or in the future a similar service.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="budget">Budget&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The requested Fund 6 budget is for wages for three months and six months of expenses. Fifty per cent of funds will be used retrospectively to cover work and expenses we are already undertaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Evaluation/Integration of Translation services: $1200 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Workflow Automation: $3000 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Process Documentation: $2200 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Train the Trainers: $850 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translations: $1250 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project Management (%8): $1000 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Software Services &amp;amp; Servers: $3000 USD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Software Services &amp;amp; Servers fees ($500 x 6 months = $3,000) includes the expenses of using a translation service (anywhere from $140USD to $240USD a month) to help streamline translations; Github; website hosting and any servers needed for translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This funding only concerns setting up and testing a translation pipeline. Further funds will be requested to continue any work beyond the three month period, either through Catalyst or other means of funding the Eastern Townhall activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-team">The Team&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A collaborative effort, the team bring a wealth of cultural and technical experience to Cardano. We are all very active in Catalyst, and community groups across our ecosystem. We are a diverse bunch united by the promise of Cardano:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yuta Yuta&lt;/strong> (@yutazz) - Japan: Cardano official ambassador, Community Co-Organiser, Catalyst Fund 2 Recipient, certified public accountant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Yan Tirta&lt;/strong> (@yantirta) - Indonesia: Cardano Indonesia community wrangler empowering his local community with education and encouragement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mie Tran&lt;/strong> (@mie.tran.0407) - Vietnam: English and International Business major with experience working with western businesses and translation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Andy Sibuea&lt;/strong> (@zicozibu) - Indonesia: Leading blockchain education beyond cryptocurrencies and across Indonesia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tim O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@tobrien) - Vietnam: No-code pioneer. Facilitator in East African Townhall (EATH).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Greg Bell&lt;/strong> (@grebel) - Australia: IT consultant, writing Catalyst Challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Seomon Blub&lt;/strong> (@seomon) - Austria: IT consultant focused on the people-ware infrastructure for sustainable communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Robert O’Brien&lt;/strong> (@wolstaeb) - New Zealand: Financial systems Software Engineer, Community Co-Organiser and Entrepreneur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stephen Whitenstall&lt;/strong> (@swhitenstall) - England: Tracks and documents Catalyst. Helping communities like Catalyst Circle and Catalyst Swarm organise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Felix Weber&lt;/strong> (@felixweber) - France: Community Manager building bridges between people. Member of the T&amp;amp;M Catalyst Circle/Swarm/School.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team represents the initial Eastern Town Hall &lt;strong>trusted seed&lt;/strong>. There are no roles, no leaders. Rather people establish themselves over time, through participation. The extended team includes professional interpreters and translators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>[1] &lt;a href="https://www.ef.com/wwen/epi/">English Proficiency Index&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[2] &lt;a href="https://c3eth.github.io/catalyst/fund6/">Eastern Townhall Catalyst Fund 6 Work&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[3] &lt;a href="https://crowdin.com/">Crowdin&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[4] &lt;a href="https://lokalise.com/">Lokalize&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[5] &lt;a href="https://poeditor.com/">PoEditor&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[6] &lt;a href="https://gitlocalize.com/">GitLozalise&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[7] &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/contribute/localization/#minimum-required-content">Kubernetes SIG Docs group&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[8] &lt;a href="https://chaoss.community/metric-project-velocity/">Project Velocity&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[9] &lt;a href="https://communityroundtable.com/best-practices/thecrs-work-out-loud-framework/">Community Metrics&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[10] &lt;a href="https://www.contributor-covenant.org/">Contributor Covernant&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>