<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>촉매 이스턴 타운 홀 – Challenge Setting Proposals</title><link>/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/</link><description>Recent content in Challenge Setting Proposals on 촉매 이스턴 타운 홀</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catalyst: Grow East Asia, Grow Cardano</title><link>/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/grow-east-asia-grow-cardano/</guid><description>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CeZynbrO-ak" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenges/fund7-challenge-setting/campaign-brief/">Fund 7 Challenge Setting&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Grow-Southeast-Asia-Grow-Cardano/367250-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $250,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-question">Challenge question:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we grow the Cardano ecosystem in East Asia in an inclusive and supportive way? The same way we do in Africa, focused initiatives!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Cardano community leans heavily toward North America and Europe. Growth elsewhere requires our support and initiative as a community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A broad spectrum of people across Asia and connected to Asia, coming together and forming teams to grow our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves some questions about the quality of participation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The number of proposals originating from East Asian participants in Project Catalyst&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The quantity and quality of funded proposals originating from East Asian teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The observed impact of funded projects (meeting their KPIs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did we increase the participation of the Cardano community and Catalyst teams with East Asian residents?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was there an increase in Daily/Monthly Active Wallets (DAW/MAW) as a proxy measure of momentum and engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Did we increase the number of Stake Pools and Stake Pool Operators based in East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We will also be asking some specific questions about the quality of the proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Is there good feedback on funded project progress, failure or success, that help us understand the nuances of deploying Cardano solutions across East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the novelty and appropriateness of solutions?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are we on track to improve the lives of people using Cardano in East Asia?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was social and environmental impact evaluation used to measure proposal performance?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the sustainability of proposals beyond the scope of Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As in Africa, raising the awareness levels of regular people in East Asia about blockchain and the Cardano network should be a priority for the Catalyst community. In this challenge, we provide funding for people who have learned about Cardano to take advantage of the community&amp;rsquo;s support and build on or use the Cardano network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The nature of the proposals for this challenge is open-ended. Their only requirement is to originate or focus on East Asia and include east Asian team members or focus on East Asian participants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, the overwhelming majority of Stake Pools reside in North America and Europe. The Cardano network will be more resilient when Stake Pools are evenly distributed across the globe. The Catalyst community needs to step up and intentionally make that happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano started life in East Asia (Japan and Hong Kong), and Emurgo focuses on East Asia. Let&amp;rsquo;s build upon that.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-this-is">What this is:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A call to action; Activate the Cardano community&amp;rsquo;s ability to recognise, reward the opportunity to make the world a better place. East Asia is fertile ground for the adoption of Cardano. The return on intention (ROI) is likely to be high because projects in young and developing economies face less economic inertia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addressing different parts of the world directly and intentionally through funding challenges makes our community more accessible. It makes us more resilient. It helps us learn and understand the needs of communities that make up our ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a vision that needs votes to become an achievement. When the challenge succeeds, the beneficiary is the whole Cardano community. It is a call to close our prejudices and open our eyes, hearts and minds to good people who lack the benefits many of us were born with—allowing others with fewer privileged circumstances to rise and succeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-team">Challenge Team&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This proposal seeks to include a challenge team. Unfortunately, the proposer&amp;rsquo;s have not had time to fully form a challenge team before the proposal goes into review. If possible, we intend to help form that team before voting commences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following individuals have offered to be on the challenge team.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Felix Weber (&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/pmd/3077912-48088?">@felixweber&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Robert O&amp;rsquo;Brien (&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/pmd/3056857-48088?">@wolstaeb&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The role of Challenge Teams is to steward the challenges in Catalyst - to present the challenge, track the progress, and report back to the community their perspective on whether the challenges were addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in being part of that team, please let us know in the comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This proposal is a copy of the &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Grow-Africa-Grow-Cardano/333079-48088">Grow Africa, Grow Cardano&lt;/a> proposed by @grebel and @archangelbob and is now one of the many &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26108">Catalyst Challenges&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Grow Social &amp; Environmental Finance</title><link>/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/grow-social-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenge-setting-proposals/grow-social-finance/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Challenge:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="/ko/catalyst/fund6/challenges/fund7-challenge-setting/campaign-brief/">Fund 7 Challenge Setting&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/SoFi-Social-Finance/368902-48088">&lt;img src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Proposal-Catalyst-blue" alt="Catalyst Proposal Badge">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Requested Amount (USD):&lt;/strong> $250,000&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-question">Challenge question&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What solutions can we build on Cardano to finance social and environmental innovation?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To address the climate emergency and the associated economic challenges, we need to build resilient financial solutions for driving change.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Impact investors, NGOs, and grassroots communities make Cardano the default choice to help transparently deliver the greatest impact.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves some guiding questions about the quality of developed solutions:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Are we on track to improve the lives of people using them?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How much financial capital is deployed to grassroots community efforts?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many gaps are filled along the impact investing value chain?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have we increased capital efficiency and lowered financing costs compared with current approaches?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Are the solutions using Cardano&amp;rsquo;s technical features to the fullest?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do teams adopt high-assurance engineering practices to develop code we can trust?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How decentralised is the solution and where are the points of control?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>At the moment there are very few usage metrics addressing Social &amp;amp; Environmental Finance (SoFi) scenarios. This challenge, therefore, will determine uptake by adopting some metrics from Decentralised Finance (DeFi) markets as a guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Daily/Monthly Active Wallets (DAW/MAW) - Measure of momentum and engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Average Order Value - Measures who are using services, how much and how often.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Total Value Locked (TLV) - Measure of confidence in DeFi market protocols.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Take Rate (Rake) - Measure of efficiency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gross Merchandise Volume (GMV) - Total value of services transacted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We will also be asking some specific questions about the proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What is the sustainability of proposals beyond the scope of Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Was social and environmental impact evaluation used to measure proposal performance?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="challenge-brief">Challenge brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This challenge is about the ways we can spark a fire under impact investing using the Cardano ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Impact investments are made with the intention to generate positive, measurable social and environmental impact alongside financial returns. While a variety of projects push for the adoption of DeFi on Cardano, can we bring to market the potential of DeFi mechanisms as a vehicle for social good?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Delivering an outcome that has an impact is a lot harder than just delivering a financial Return-on-Investment, even a small one. Impact investing (according to the World Economic Forum) is hindered by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The lack and/or high cost of trustworthy data on the social or environmental results of investment, making credible accounting of impacts difficult.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Challenges around the “attribution” of impact – meaning the allocation of an impact-related claim to an investor risks “double-counting.”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Roadblocks in monetizing impacts – illiquid impact markets, uncertain returns, high transaction costs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Propose market solutions, financial mechanisms, or means of measuring impact. Think about how these can be deployed at scale to affect positively millions of people. Think about how the results of your proposal can be embedded or reused in different market contexts, or integrated with existing providers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Igniting impact investment on Cardano will provide capital to address the world’s most pressing challenges in sectors such as sustainable agriculture, renewable energy, conservation, microfinance, and affordable and accessible basic services including housing, healthcare, and education.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To achieve impact requires cooperation and collaboration, something Cardano can enable. Could the answer to better managing the world’s resources lie not in government or big investors but instead in technologies that empower peer-to-peer assistance. Community-based finance or data-driven crowdfunding for instance. How can we leverage the awesome power of the Cardano ecosystem to be that catalyst?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>