<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tòa thị chính Catalyst Eastern – Fund 6 Challenges</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/</link><description>Recent content in Fund 6 Challenges on Tòa thị chính Catalyst Eastern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catalyst: Cardano Emerging Threat Alarm</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/emerging-threats/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/emerging-threats/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để giúp các bên liên quan xác định các mối đe dọa có hệ thống nghiêm trọng rõ rệt đối với Cardano blockchain trước khi một mối đe dọa vượt qua hệ thống?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>$50,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26110">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26110/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Blockchain systems are a complex amalgam of technological, economic and social components that rely and are used by many stakeholders from different geographies and backgrounds. These systems are not isolated from the real world and unexpected threats may emerge from the dynamic interaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano stakeholders (users, SPOs, DApp developers, partners, Exchanges, governments, companies) need a resilient system that is able to identify and grade developing threats to its own existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cardano complexity increases with decentralization, native tokens, multi-asset support, smart contracts and new users. Threats will emerge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Stable evolution. Cardano successfully onboards new users, developers, DApps, tokens, SPOs, oracles, companies. Threats are identified&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we should be asking ourselves: Did we manage to create a simple mechanism for identifying novel, emerging systemic threats to the Cardano ecosystem? We can&amp;rsquo;t see the future now, but as events unfold we may be able to use our collective wisdom and senses to detect new dangers for the Cardano blockchain and its usage.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of potential threats that have been submitted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grading of the submitted threats by urgency&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of threats that have been identified as serious and systemic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grouping of threat sources into categories and types to determine wider danger areas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Cardano stakeholders interacting with the threat alert mechanism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Catalyst proposals submitted and accepted for funding in subsequent funding rounds to directly address the most pressing identified threats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Cardano-Emerging-Threat-Alarm/340926-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Catalyst value onboarding</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/catalyst-value-onboarding/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/catalyst-value-onboarding/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Cách để khuyến khích sự tham gia có ý nghĩa từ phía các thành viên của cộng đồng cho Dự án Catalyst trong hai quỹ đầu tư tiếp theo?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>$75,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26106">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26106/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The growth of Cardano depends on meaningful participation from proposers, advisors, and voters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a strong funnel to motivate, inform and direct new participants towards providing a contribution that improves Catalyst&amp;rsquo;s ROI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metric-to-measure">Key metric to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To assess ROI of this challenge we will ask ourselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did we manage to increase meaningful participation from proposers, advisors, and voters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of total number of new participants:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What % active community advisers?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What % watch townhalls?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What % vote?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What % proposes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What % becomes a referrer?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How can we increase meaningful participation from proposers, advisors, and voters?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How do new people learn about Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can we provide a central source of constantly updated information in different formats(text, video, p2p)?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Education and onboarding through timely YouTube content&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Better user experience through hardware wallet support, Daedalus/yoroi support ect.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reddit presence offering reliable information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mentoring programs matching veteran Catalysts and new Catalysts.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25944">Fund5: Catalyst value onboarding&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25872">Fund4: Catalyst value onboarding&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Cải thiện và phát triển khả năng kiểm toán</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/improve-auditability/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/improve-auditability/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để quá trình kiểm tra các đề xuất được tài trợ hiệu quả, phân bổ và minh bạch?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$100,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26119">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26119/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When Fund7 happens we will be close to 100 funded proposals. It is extremely important that these proposals are evaluated/audited to see if they are delivering and if the ROI is being in line with what has been established initialy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, IOG is in charge of monitoring the development of these funded proposals, but when there are hundreds of funded proposals this will be an overwhelming work for IOG.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Auditability challenge aims to ensure transparency in the use of Cardano&amp;rsquo;s treasury resources, which will allow the Cardano community to have more information on the development of funded proposals through a checks and balances system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some directions that this challenge can take:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Podcasts with teams from funded proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Smart contract audits.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Platforms / Websites that perform:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Reporting on metrics, spending of financial resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Metrics on the development of Dapps (txs, volume, unique wallets, etc …)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Metrics on Number of onboarded developers, number of commits in funded proposal repositories.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Social media engagement indicators metrics.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s important that the funded proposals are evaluated to see if they are delivering what was established in their mission..&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Several projects evaluating funded proposals, providing reports, articles and metrics on the development and implementation of the projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="number-of-funded-proposals-audited">Number of funded proposals audited&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Considering that the idea is to audit and report on the development of proposals in different challenges, it is important that success metrics are thought out in relation to each challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="number-of-reports-articles-and-videospodcasts-on">Number of reports, articles and videos/podcasts on:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Achievements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Financials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of onboarded developers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of commits in funded proposal repositories (Github)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Indicators of: transactions, volume and unique wallets interacting with dapps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of smart contracts audited.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social media engagement indicators.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/25946/stage/unspecified">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: DApps &amp; Integrations</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/dapps-integrations/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/dapps-integrations/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>What applications will provide the most value for end users in 2021?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>$250,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26103">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26103/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tóm-tắt-chiến-dịch">Tóm tắt chiến dịch&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Quality Dapps and integrations will increase utility &amp;amp; adoption of Cardano.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Các ứng dụng mới và khả thi được xây dựng hàng đầu của Cardano thu hút nhiều người dùng. Integrations manage to pull in more adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metric-to-measure">Key metric to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To assess the challenge we will be asking ourselves: Did our efforts manage to attract users to the platform? Did our efforts result in new, viable applications built on top of Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let an &amp;ldquo;application output&amp;rdquo; and an &amp;ldquo;application transaction&amp;rdquo; be an outputs and transactions that use the applications' script addresses; and an &amp;ldquo;application token&amp;rdquo; be a token that&amp;rsquo;s issued by the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="usage-of-applications-developed-during-the-challenge">Usage of applications developed during the challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application output&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Total volume of Ada involved in application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Total/growth of resource usage by applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of distinct addresses mentioned in application transactions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the application uses tokens:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of application tokens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number/growth of distinct addresses holding application tokens&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="viability-of-applications-developed-during-the-challenge">Viability of applications developed during the challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How many of the applications are still being developed at the end of 2021?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the applications made a profit for their creators?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the teams which built the applications grew during 2021?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many of the teams which built the applications built (or plan to build) another application?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What are the key applications that underpin the application ecosystem on other platforms?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are the most profitable or most used applications on other ecosystems?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What needs do users of Cardano have that could be solved by new applications?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What applications deliver the highest amount of value with the least amount of technical sophistication?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Swaps, both simple and fancy variants (multi-party etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Escrow, both simple and fancy variants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrations with existing products&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25941">Fund 5 DApps &amp;amp; Integrations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25869">Fund 4 DApps &amp;amp; Integrations&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25797">Fund 3 DApps Creation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25652">Fund 2 Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25604">Fund 1 Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Developer ecosystem</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/developer-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/developer-ecosystem/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để tạo ra trải nghiệm tích cực cho nhà phát triển giúp họ tập trung vào vào việc xây dựng thành công các ứng dụng?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$1,005,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26094">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26094/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Creating an awesome experience that incentives developers, will lead to increased developer adoption, productivity, and creativity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Liveliness. Happy energized developers making money and achieving their goals, mutual help, collaboration, and a shared feeling of success. A feeling of unexpected innovation happening &amp;ldquo;on it&amp;rsquo;s own&amp;rdquo;. A wide variety of resources are provided for developers allowing them to focus on business value they can generate and not on infrastructure&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano has a thriving ecosystem of infrastructure companies that don&amp;rsquo;t need to be subsidized by grants and are able to scale their businesses by monetizing the services that they provide. They are attracting developers to the ecosystem and educating them on how to build applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metric-to-measure">Key metric to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves: Did we manage to make it easier for developers to build on top of Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Filling in gaps defined in the exploration stage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of developers actively building on top of Cardano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of repos on Github using the tooling. (Month over month increase)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce wait time of unanswered communications with developers to 24 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A sense of community and conversations. Having people around to talk with.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What are the the tools that we need to prioritize first&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How do we attract developers from outside of our current community to participate in Catalyst?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What do developers want, and how do they get it from the Cardano dev ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What would make it a developer motivated to grind through the docs and code no matter how hard it is to create an app?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What are enterprise dev managers looking for in order to be able to build out enterprise projects - either internal or commercial?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developer productivity: IDE&amp;rsquo;s, scripts to automate stuff.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Knowledge base &amp;amp; Documentation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deployment, testing, and monitoring frameworks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Samples, recipes and templates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hackathons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DEFI and tokenization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dashboards&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API&amp;rsquo;s, and oracles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support structures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incentivization structures&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25939">Fund 5 Developer Ecosystem Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25868">Fund 4 Developer Ecosystem Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25805">Fund 3 Developer Ecosystem Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25652">Fund 2 Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25604">Fund 1 Challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Hộp công cụ khởi nghiệp Công nghệ sổ cái phân tán</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/dlt-enterpreneurship/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/dlt-enterpreneurship/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>How can early stage entrepreneurs develop their skills to execute &amp;amp; communicate great ideas so voters/stakeholders value the project?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>$150,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26113">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26113/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Whatever your background, confidently communicating all the important elements of an early stage venture can be overwhelming for inexperienced entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More should be done to help an increasingly diverse group of Project Catalyst entrepreneurs, at different stages of self-development, plus their teams and stakeholders to collaborate and communicate effectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is important to Project Catalyst as, over time, the strongest ideas will be those that are the most coherently communicated and which ultimately resonate clearly with voters - particularly Expert evaluators!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This challenge seeks to help inexperienced entrepreneurs to learn and apply vital entrepreneurship skills so they can collaborate with teams and stakeholders on meaningful Catalyst projects. This also helps ensure sustainable impact and a positive return on investment and intention is made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Entrepreneurs strengths are ambition and vision but often lack structure to communicate ideas clearly enough to win voter hearts &amp;amp; minds&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Higher quality of proposal submitted to Catalyst so entrepreneurs become confident presenting project principles, USP, strategy, objectives&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of users, using the tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Difference in score of applicants using the toolbox and those not using the tools.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gaps that are filled in the entrepreneurial skills base of project teams from the start of ideation through project delivery.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sustainability of venture plans beyond the scope of Catalyst development project.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/DLT-Entrepreneurship-Toolbox/341809-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Mở rộng quy mô các trung tâm cộng đồng của Cardano</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/scaleup-community-hubs/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/scaleup-community-hubs/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để khuyến khích các Trung tâm cộng đồng địa phương thúc đẩy việc áp dụng và nhận thức về Cardano trong 6 tháng tới?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26118">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26118/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Out of the world&amp;rsquo;s approximately 7.8 billion inhabitants, 6.45 billion do not speak English.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Living in the Western world, we forget this fact regularly, and many of us have never even considered it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s consider it now and start to build an ecosystem that is truly global, allowing everyone to participate to the best of their ability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you drive adoption at the ground level, you are doing more than just &amp;lsquo;building cool products&amp;rsquo;, you are empowering people to change their lives in ways they could have never imagined by themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Without users on the ground level, we are building niche products serving mostly technical people with blockchain expertise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Local Community Hubs across the world where the average person can take part in their own language and with their own cultural understanding&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How many new Hubs were launched in the next 6 months?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many developers did this community-focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many new users of Cardano were onboarded?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What was the total reach of the Hub&amp;rsquo;s initial marketing launch?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many external organizations did this community-focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25873">Fund4: Local Community Centers&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Scale-UP-Cardano-s-Community-Hubs/352534-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Mở rộng quy mô hệ sinh thái Tài chính phi tập trung của Cardano</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/scaleup-defi/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/scaleup-defi/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để có thể khuyến khích các nhóm Tài chính phi tập trung xây dựng / triển khai các giải pháp tài chính mở trên Cardano trong 6 tháng tới?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26109">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26109/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Currently the vast majority of DeFi dapps and currency flows occur on the Ethereum blockchain, however due to congestion and increased transaction fees, the use of DeFi is increasingly elitized, leaving out the people who could most benefit from it. benefit from this, the unbanked.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s important b/c Defi dApps provide trustless on-demand access to financial services for global users w/ Total Value Locked ~$25billion&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A competitive environment for DeFi on Cardano with an emphasis on cross-collaboration &amp;amp; driving composability across protocols.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How many DeFi protocols were launched on Cardano mainnet within 6 months from this DeFi focused community challenge?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many daily active users are the DeFi protocols funded in this cohort attracting?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How much Total Value Locked (TVL) are the funded DeFi protocols able to capture 1 month post launch on Cardano mainnet? (measure again at 3 months, 6 months and 1 year post-implementation to glean complete insights on proposal challenge effectiveness)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many DeFi developers did this community focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many FinTech/DeFi development firms did this community focused challenge bring into the Cardano ecosystem?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25948">Fund5: Scale-UP Cardano&amp;rsquo;s DeFi Ecosystem&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Scale-UP-Cardano-s-DeFi-Ecosystem/333399-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Những mô hình kinh doanh mã thông báo không thể thay thế</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/nft-business-models/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/nft-business-models/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>What non-Art use cases of NFTs can distinguish Cardano as the blockchain of choice for NFT based businesses?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26115">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26115/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Propose a means or way to drive business use cases on Cardano that have NFT usage as a core component and can act as an onramp to the Cardano ecosystem. This can include any business model based on NFTs. Think about how this is implemented at scale drawing millions of users, who, once onboard, can become customers for dApps, tools, DeFi and other services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Challenge is about building recurring businesses that incorporate NFTs on the Cardano ecosystem. The more types of NFTs that are circulating on Cardano will increase the utility of Cardano and ADA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-should-be-proposed">What should be proposed?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Proposals should be framed towards specific use-cases, and the community will know of specific cases where NFTs can be used to solve various problems. Focusing on NFTs in general may be most productive, with a strong focus on business models that rely on NFTs as a core component of most transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>NFTs have the potential to create businesses with recurring NFT use requirements which increase utilization of the Cardano blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many high quality ideas will be proposed that can substantially grow Cardano&amp;rsquo;s user-base, network-utility, network-value &amp;amp; ADA circulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The number of proposals that directly address NFT use cases in a quantifiable manner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The quality of proposals measured by community interest and engagement.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Results of any Fund7 funded projects significantly impacting NFT utility on the Cardano blockchain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/NFT-Business-models/352815-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Atala-PRISM-DID-Mass-Scale-Adoption/334524-48088">Fund4 Challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Phát triển Châu Phi, Phát triển Cardano</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/grow-africa/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/grow-africa/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để ươm mầm và phát triển Cardano ở Châu Phi?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$200,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26108">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26108/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="châu-phi-là-một-mảnh-đất-màu-mỡ-trong-việc-áp-dụng-cardano">Châu Phi là một mảnh đất màu mỡ trong việc áp dụng Cardano.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Có sự tài trợ tập trung vào Châu Phi là một viễn cảnh mà đôi bên cùng có lợi. Châu Phi có lợi vì có được sự hỗ trợ. Dự án thương mại đã được xây dựng ở Châu Phi sẽ có lợi vì họ nhận được những tín hiệu ủng hộ từ cộng đồng. Những người nắm giữ Cardano sẽ có lợi khi có một môi trường khuyến khích họ được áp dụng ở mọi nơi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tập trung vào Châu Phi là một chiến lược đã được đề xuất và được phát triển rộng rãi bởi IOG và Charles Hoskinson&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ROI sẽ khá cao bởi vì những dự án tài trợ cộng đồng tốt hơn nên được vận hành trên nền kinh tế trẻ và đang phát triển.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="đây-là-gì">Đây là gì:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Một lời kêu gọi để kích hoạt khả năng của cộng đồng Cardano để nhận diện, nhìn thấy rủi ro và trao thưởng cho cơ hội này để làm cho thế giới trở thành một nơi tốt đẹp hơn.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dự-án-này-không-phải-là">Dự án này không phải là:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dự án này không cần sự làm việc tích cực của người đề xuất, nó là một tầm nhìn cần những phiếu bầu để trở thành một thành tựu. Nếu thành công thì cả cộng đồng Cardano sẽ nhận được lợi ích từ nó. Đây là một lời kêu gọi để dập tắt định kiến và mở rộng tầm nhìn, trái tim và khối óc với những người tốt nhưng thiếu những lợi ích về môi trường mà nhiều người trong chúng ta sinh ra. Giving them an opportunity to show that circumstances are not something they need charity to rise above and succeed. All that is required is the equal opportunity to succeed or fail that many of the rest of us enjoy, but with their hinderances and hurdles lessened and their choices remaining in their own hands.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="regardless-of-whether-it-succeeds-or-fails">Regardless of whether it succeeds or fails:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have had my eyes opened and my mind changed about the potential of Africa. From Africa&amp;rsquo;s bankers in the west, ex-pats with vision and heart, youth with passions, documentaries that challenged my assumptions and Cardano community members with so much to give.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Cardano shines when adoption is global. Africa currently has young entrepreneurs, great growth potential and a government contract imminent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Cardano is considered the best public block-chain operating in Africa&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cardano projects in Africa are not isolated but networked and growing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of purely African participants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of Outside African participants with a significant partnership with African residents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Feedback on progress from successful proposals regardless of failure or success&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Novelty and appropriateness of solutions (hard to quantify, easy to see)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of African Fund5 proposals that do not need further funding to keep operating&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25947">Fund 5: Grow Africa, Grow Cardano&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Grow-Africa-Grow-Cardano/333079-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Quan hệ đối tác cho việc phát triển toàn cầu</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/partnerships-for-adoption/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/partnerships-for-adoption/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>How can Cardano enter in global partnerships with United Nations Development Programme and World Bank Group, to leverage mass adoption?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fund Size: &lt;strong>$30,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26114">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26114/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Partnership protocols aim to support nation building and support sustainable development goals by providing blockchain solutions to local governments and populations. Cardano´s work would be part of wider development projects undertaking. Proposers to provide a partnership framework model for each of the international bodies in question for Cardano Foundation further implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Collaboration with International bodies working in the developing world will accelerate mass adoption for Cardano´s blockchain solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Establishment of Local Community Centers in 130 countries backed by Cardano Foundation working in synergy with international bodies&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>10 proposals put forward for voting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partnerships formalized with in 3 months by Cardano Foundation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local Community Centers established with in 6 months&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Partnerships-for-Global-Adoption/340504-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Rủi ro: Khi tất cả đang bị gặp trắc trở</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/disaster/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/disaster/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>How can we help SPOs tackle risks &amp;amp; plan, develop and participate in disaster recovery tests in a safe hiccup-free and decentralized manner?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$150,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26117">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26117/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Disaster recovery (DR) is an area of security planning that aims to protect an organization from the effects of significant negative events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having a disaster recovery strategy in place enables an organization to maintain or quickly resume mission-critical functions following a disruption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano as a proposed financial operating system for the world must have several layers of built in redundancies even for events that may seem remote or very unlikely now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although a testnet exists, real-world conditions can never be fully replicated. Maybe proposers can develop a way of incentivizing further SPO participation in the Cardano testnet and more simulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A system that aspires to become a global financial operating system, must be stress tested. Running nodes should be prepared for disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Likely points of failure identified. Disaster communication channels set up. Recovery procedures identified. Testing procedures developed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>has a methodology for decentralized stress testing of the main network been developed - by and for stakepool operators?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>are participating stakepools being rewarded for taking part in mainnet disaster recovery tests?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>are there enough incentives in place for participating in the Cardano testnet?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>are stakepool operators able to conduct limited network stress testing (overload, disconnection, bad actor, DDoS … scenarios) and are they rewarded for participating in these tests (instead of being punished by losing slots)?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have new guidelines, recommendations and emergency communication channels been established for stakepool operators who wish to take part in these emergency preparations?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>has a a dedicated risk-assessment and risk-management team been set up?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have protocols been developed for recovering from an emergency situation that could take most of the main network offline?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have proposals been developed for building in different kinds of redundancies?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have new benchmarks been developed to measure whether the Cardano stake pool network is safer, more stable, more resilient and more decentralized?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>have wider screening of risk sources been performed: CyberSecurity, political and regulatory risks, internet-related risks etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Disaster-When-all-is-at-stake/351012-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Thiết lập thử thách trong Quỹ đầu tư số 7</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/fund7-challenge-setting/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/fund7-challenge-setting/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Những thử thách nào mà cộng đồng nên ưu tiên giải quyết trong Quỹ đầu tư số 7?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$5,400,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26120">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26120/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Community defined challenges are critical for Cardano community self-governance, and generate a unique way to achieve Cardano&amp;rsquo;s mission.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Challenge setting is different from other challenges as it&amp;rsquo;s about proposing new challenges, whether regular challenges are about proposing initiatives to address challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a proposal is accepted by the community, the proposing team has an opportunity to receive a &amp;ldquo;Challenge team&amp;rdquo; incentive of $2,500 worth of ada, if the following conditions are met:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The challenge team presents the challenge to the community at the start of the following fund.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The challenge team facilitates a challenge-focused breakout session in one of the after townhalls.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The challenge team leads a challenge retrospective session during the next fund&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;retrospective week&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The challenge team facilitates a session with the proposing teams that received funding for the challenge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The challenge team tracks the key metrics as reported by funded proposals, 3 months after receiving funding and presents their reflection on whether the Challenge is getting addressed and highlight teams that are making significant headway in their approach.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These activities might seem complicated, but you will receive guidelines, training and support from the Catalyst team and community. All you need is a willingness to represent the challenge in a fair and balanced way and a desire to participate. Once the conditions are met, your team will be eligible to receive the reward.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The community votes to include important and engaging challenges that inspire impactful and original proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To assess ROI of this challenge we will ask ourselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How well did the selected challenges perform in terms of proposal quality and community engagement?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the average Community Advisor score for the top 10% proposed Challenges?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the average Community Advisor score for the top 10% proposals generated to address the challenge?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How much voter engagement did the challenge generate?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How many proposals in the challenge were approved by the community, compared to the overall budget of the challenge? (Challenge overage)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What challenges will engage the highest number of voters?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Which challenges, if addressed, will provide a springboard for Cardano adoption?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Which challenges, if addressed, will advance Cardano&amp;rsquo;s mission?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25946">Fund 5: Fund6 challenge setting&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25874">Fund 4: Fund5 challenge setting&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25800">Fund 3: F3: Community choice&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Thử thách siêu dữ liệu</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/metadata-challenge/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/metadata-challenge/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào chúng ta có thể sử dụng giao dịch siêu dữ liệu để giải quyết các vấn đề trong thế giới thực?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$100,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26107">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26107/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With transaction metadata, Cardano can be utilized as a network to store small proofs of events or documents. This utility has been used in the past to implement product anti-counterfeit solutions as well as traceability solutions. Smart contracts are not necessary to take advantage of this functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This challenge is for you if you have problems that involve:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Demonstrate to external parties that a specific document has not been tampered with.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demonstrate to external parties that a specific event took place.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demonstrate to external parties that a document existed at a specific date/time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demonstrate any or all of the above without revealing the document or the event&amp;rsquo;s data (because of privacy concerns).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>IOHK is pleased to announce that we will support and provide expert advice to the proposal winners. The same team that created the New Balance and Beefchain solutions will be offering these services to the proposal winners for 6 months after the winners are announced:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 hr a week of expert advice from IOHK&amp;rsquo;s solutions architects and technical consultants.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email address for offline queries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Architectural/design/technical reviews.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prototypes are built that utilize metadata to solve real life problems. The prototypes are presented to the Catalyst community in any of the town halls.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Potential amount of users that can be brought onto Cardano.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community feedback (positive/negative) about the prototypes after presentation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Followup Catalyst proposals.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What is the target audience?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Who are the potential users of the platform?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the problem that metadata is solving?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Why does the target audience care about the solution? Why would they install/use the solution?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does the solution need hardware components?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What would retain the user on the solution? That is, after installation, why would you keep using it? What value does it bring to the user (continuously)?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Traceability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Product Authentication&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auditable decentralized document workflows (i.e. HelloSign solutions or similar).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25945">Fund 5: Metadata challenge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Tiếp cận nhà đề xuất</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/proposer-outreach/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/proposer-outreach/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để khuyến khích các doanh nhân từ bên ngoài hệ sinh thái Cardano gửi đề xuất cho Catalyst trong hai quỹ đầu tư tiếp theo?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$100,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26105">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26105/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Outside proposers will inject vitality and diversity to the community while increasing the overall quality of proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cardano has ambitious plans to reach 1 billion people. To make this goal a reality, we must attract the brightest entrepreneurs from across the globe and encourage them to submit ideas which will have a positive impact on the ecosystem. The best ideas will be funded, providing entrepreneurs with a more democratized route to capital and ensuring that location is not a barrier to entry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We must increase brand awareness of Catalyst amongst the entrepreneur community, via multi platform proposer outreach campaigns. From content creation to media coverage, hackathons and live events - we want the community to submit their ideas that will attract and engage this audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bright entrepreneurs, and specialized firms from across the globe learn about Catalyst and submit high impact proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metric-to-measure">Key metric to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To assess ROI of this challenge we will ask ourselves:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did we get proposals from outside our ecosystem?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Media coverage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ideas submitted from new members of the community.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community advisor rating of top 10% of &amp;ldquo;outsider&amp;rdquo; proposals&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-challenges">Prior Challenges&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25943">Fund 5: Proposer Outreach&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25871">Fund 4: Proposer Outreach&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Tài chính phi tập trung và Khoản vay vi mô cho Châu Phi</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/defi-microlending/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/defi-microlending/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$90,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How can we enable the creation of micro-lending and Defi dApp solutions that fits the African setting?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26112">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26112/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Microlending and DeFi dApps targeted specifically to the African context &amp;amp; based on historical cultural norms will accelerate user adoption&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Businesses are confident to submit well-researched proposals that address the African micro-lending and decentralized finance context&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Submitted proposals well researched, viable and addresses traditional African financial cultural norms and practices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 or more successfully funded micro-lending and Defi dApp launched within the next 3 funding rounds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minimum 50% user adoption in funded proposal&amp;rsquo;s target market within 2 years&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/DeFi-and-Microlending-for-Africa/340138-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Tài nguyên đa ngôn ngữ</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/multilingual-resources/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/multilingual-resources/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để thúc đẩy những người không nói tiếng Anh học hỏi và phát triển hệ sinh thái Cardano trong vòng 3 đến 6 tháng tới?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$75,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26111">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26111/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ngôn ngữ tiếng Anh có thể là rào cản cho nhiều người trên thế giới khi họ muốn tìm hiểu về Cardano và công nghệ blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least in Spanish there are no resources for people who might want to learn how to code smart contracts with Plutus or Marlowe for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Multilingual platforms will allow non-English speakers to learn about Cardano and increase its adoption worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Increased adoption and community engagement of non-English speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increased amount of resources in a variety of languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the end of this challenge, we will be asking ourselves: Did we manage to make it easier for non-English speakers to build and grow the Cardano community in their local areas?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Number of non-English speakers joining Cardano community&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Number of courses translated to different languages, from programming to stakepool operation and so on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A sense of community and conversations. Having people around to talk with.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Multilingual-resources/341725-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: Đưa ra quyết định phân bổ</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/distributed-decision/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/distributed-decision/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Làm cách nào để giúp cộng đồng Catalyst làm tốt hơn trong việc đưa ra quyết định phân bổ trong hai vòng Catalyst tiếp theo?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ: &lt;strong>$75,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26104">Campaign page&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26104/stage/unspecified">browse ideas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campaign-brief">Campaign Brief&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>High-quality and decentralized decision-making, will increase treasury ROI and legitimize decentralized governance.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-success-looks-like">How success looks like&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The community is consciously improving decision-making processes while growing a group of committed and collaborative leaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To assess ROI of this challenge we will ask ourselves: Did we get better at distributed decision making?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community confidence: avg rating or % of Catalyst members who approve of overall results of a funding round.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community participation: number of Catalyst participants contributing to improving Catalyst decision making systems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Measured overall&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Impact of individual initiatives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proof of iteration: round over round, is there evidence that &amp;ldquo;pain points&amp;rdquo; are evolving? (Failure would look like seeing the same problems emerging each funding round)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Re-election rates: if proposers receive subsequent funding, this can be seen as a sign of success&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Embracing failure: is the community able to see value in &amp;amp; learn from proposals that did not work out?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="guiding-questions">Guiding questions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How do we encourage people to participate in decision making?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do we ensure the group of decision makers is diverse and accessible to newcomers?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How can we ensure that the Catalyst process keeps iterating to improve?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How will we include the community in decision making?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="potential-directions">Potential directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software that supports decision making or iteration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Experiments in social, collaboration, or meeting structures that encourage improved decision making&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community advisor training&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Low effort ways to engage voters in assessing proposals and tapping into existing insights.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="prior-campaigns">Prior Campaigns&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25942">Fund 5 Distributed decision making&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/25870">Fund 4 Distributed decision making&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Catalyst: ỨNG DỤNG QUY MÔ LỚN CỦA Atala PRISM DID</title><link>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/atala-prism-did/campaign-brief/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/vi/catalyst/fund6/challenges/atala-prism-did/campaign-brief/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Điều gì sẽ thúc đẩy việc áp dụng quy mô lớn các ID phi tập trung trên Cardano?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giá trị quỹ:&lt;strong>$250,000 USD paid in Ada&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/campaign-home/26116">Trang dự án&lt;/a> và &lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/ideas/top/campaign-filter/byids/campaigns/26116/stage/unspecified">duyệt các ý tưởng&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tóm-tắt-dự-án">Tóm tắt dự án&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Đề xuất một phương tiện hoặc cách thức để thúc đẩy việc sử dụng DID trên quy mô lớn như một phương tiện hỗ trợ dễ sử dụng cho hệ sinh thái Cardano (Atala PRISM là phù hợp nhất khi phát hành). Điều này bao gồm nhiều phương pháp hỗ trợ người dùng hoặc công ty với ID phi tập trung để xác định được sự tự chủ về kỹ thuật số của họ. Hãy nghĩ về cách điều này được triển khai trên quy mô lớn thu hút hàng triệu người dùng, những người khi đã tham gia, có thể trở thành khách hàng của dApp, công cụ, DeFi và các dịch vụ khác.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chúng ta là cộng đồng về các nhà lãnh đạo tư tưởng và đã đến lúc thể hiện những ý tưởng của chúng ta bằng hành động. Sử dụng công nghệ Nhận dạng Phân quyền (DID) để thiết lập sự hiện diện và quyền sở hữu của thông tin Nhận dạng Cá nhân (PII) thúc đẩy sự phân cấp của các tổ chức; mang lợi ích cho các cá nhân và các tổ chức.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Challenge is about small ways we can incorporate DIDs into the Cardano ecosystem to start the ground swell at the grassroots that demands PII be secured and controlled with DID technologies and standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is about &lt;strong>signaling to the world&lt;/strong> that the Cardano community plans mass-adoption of DID that is interchangeable, interoperable (by WW DID standards) and &lt;strong>we care deeply that the origin of our personal DID is tied to our home blockchain—Cardano.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While we prefer to support Atala PRISM&amp;rsquo;s instantiation of DID, this is more about building ideas and concepts that require DID to draw users to the Cardano platform. And since PRISM is building to the open standards, those are available for anyone to imagine possibilities and offer proposals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It won&amp;rsquo;t be lost on IOHK how the community responses to this Challenge. Should IOHK see a ground swell of great ideas and proposals, that could help them justify expediting timelines for their planned open sourcing of PRISM components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-is-it-important">Why is it important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Atala PRISM DID is a gateway to the Cardano blockchain and ecosystem. Building technology and marketecture that on-boards users is crucial.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-does-success-look-like">How does success look like?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many high quality ideas will be proposed that can substantially grow Cardano&amp;rsquo;s user-base, network-utility, network-value &amp;amp; ADA circulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-metrics-to-measure">Key Metrics to measure&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The number of proposals that directly address DID use cases in a quantifiable manner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The quality of proposals measured by community interest and engagement.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Results of any Fund7 funded projects significantly impacting mass-scale adoption of DID&amp;rsquo;s and their utility on the Cardano blockchain.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Atala-PRISM-DID-Mass-Scale-Adoption/350613-48088">Original challenge setting proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>